How we doing? Go ahead. Who wants to
fire? First question away there.
>> I'll get you. Go ahead. Started now. Uh
this off seasonason of course you've got
Will Anderson Jr. CJ Stout and uh
potential contract extensions there. How
are you kind of uh looking to handle
that situation or looking at that
situation?
>> Yeah, I mean we haven't typically talked
publicly about contracts and anybody's
particular situation. I would say those
two players are really good players.
They've helped our program. um win a
number of football games. So, we'll kind
of take it one day at a time and just
try to piece the team together and, you
know, try to do ultimately we feel makes
the most sense for our team and the
organization. So, um no timetable on
anything. Um but, you know, we'll kind
of handle business as business is being
done.
>> With you guys kind of double dipping
last year in the draft with wide
receiver, can you speak to like maybe
how that helped in terms of, you know, a
young quarterback in their development?
Yeah, I'd say those two it's probably
more happen stance more than anything
else. Um like we don't go into the draft
and say we're going to draft X, Y, and
Z. Try to grade the players, try to take
them off the board as they come. Um in
that particular situation, those are two
players that we really like. So, you
know, this program is not about one
player. It's not about helping one
position group. It's not about helping
one individual. It's about how do we put
together a good consistent team on a
year-to-year basis. And we feel that
we've been able to do that. And that'll
be the goal here this off seasonason as
well. So, um, those two guys are, you
think, are going to be two pretty good
young players in Jay Nol and Higs. Um,
you know, I'm sure there's some other
players that are here this week that
we're going to have an opportunity to
bring in our building and, you know,
hopefully they can help our program in
some capacity.
>> Nick, in saying that, your offensive
line, you need to shore up your
offensive line, I would say. Uh would
you would you say if you had somebody
that presented themselves at a different
position like the best in that that
position dropped in so late would you
would you say you guys were leaning more
towards offensive lineman or somebody
who was the best the best available at
that time?
>> Yeah, we're typically taking the best
players. Um I would say as it pertains
to the offensive line. I mean honestly
it's probably one of the best years we
had since I've been there. Um we played
you know I think we gave up the least
amount of sacks um in or second in the
history of the organization. We had the
most improvement from a sack production
from one year to the next. I think it
was us and the Bears. So, I mean,
honestly, our offensive line actually
played pretty good last year. So, maybe
I was looking at different film, but you
know, we're going to look at who we feel
are the best players that we think are
going to help us and, you know, try to
put together a good team.
>> How do you play two close games with the
Jaguars this year? What stood out about
the way they were able to turn it
around?
>> Yeah, I'd say they got a great program.
I mean, what you know, Liam and James
and honestly, Tony Pelli have done kind
of building the program going into the
season, we felt that this was going to
be a much improved team, or at least I
thought that, and it kind of came to
fruition. Um, they're tough, they're
physical, um, they play the right way,
they're well coached, they're
disciplined. I mean, anytime you win 13
games in this league says a lot about
like where your program is. So, I mean,
they earn the AFC South this year with
their performance. Um, I think our
really division overall is going to be
probably as competitive as any of the
league next year. I mean, you mentioned
the Jaguars. I mean, they're defending
division champs, made the playoffs. I
mean, the Colts, I mean, they're a good
team. I think Tennessee is going to be
much improved, but we got a lot of
respect for Jacksonville and their
program and what they did. And, you
know, we understand the challenges that,
you know, what it's going to take if
you're have to play a good brand of
football on a week, you know, weekly
basis to beat the Jaguars. So, a lot of
lot of credit to them and a lot of
respect for their program. How do you
evaluate tackling in a college prospect?
And with so little tackling done in
practice, do you still see guys improve
at tackling in the NFL?
>> The the short answer is yes. And I'll
give you one illustrative example. So
when we drafted Petri in 22, really good
player. So his rookie year, it wasn't
great. And he'll tell you that. I think
he led the league in missed tackles. He
I think had 150 some odd tackles, but he
also led the league in missed tackles.
I'd say fast forward here, like he's
probably one of the best tacklers that
we have on a team. So, it's a skill that
you can improve. I think it goes back to
coaching. Our defensive staff does a
great job of focusing on certain
fundamentals and techniques and then you
see that transfer over into our play.
So, it absolutely is a skill that you
can improve. Tackling is really about a
mindset. Um, and there's certain
tackling can be taught a lot of
different ways. You know, there's you
can approach a ball carrier, break down,
you can shoot your shot, go to the near
hip. I mean, it all depends on what your
philosophy is, but as long as you have
the right mentality and the right
mindset, you can improve any skill that
you're deficient in, which I would say
tackling certainly qualifies.
>> Obviously aren't in this position, but
in terms of trying to evaluate college
quarterbacks, what's the toughest thing
now given how things have changed in
college?
>> Yeah, the big thing is what are they
being coached to do? What are they being
asked to do? and how much of the system
with which they play in can transfer
over into our league. I mean, this
league is really the situational element
is probably more magnified and more
pronounced. Third down, red area and a
game at a half situations. Those happen
more in our league than they do in
college football. I mean, you can go
look for them in college football, but a
quarterback a lot of times isn't really
put in those situations. But if you have
the ability to evaluate them and through
that lens, then that's certainly
valuable. But there's a certain level of
retraining how you play the position.
And look, the reality is, I mean, the
quarterbacks are going to play under
center in our league. So, and in
college, I don't know what the
percentages are. I'm sure there's a
bunch of that out there, but the
majority of them are playing not under
center. They're playing from the gun.
So, there's a little bit of a transition
there that takes place. Some can handle
that. And again, there's technique,
there's footwork that's involved. I
mean, how do you position your feet,
your stance, how do you get away from
center? I mean, those are all relevant.
It might seem like minor things, but
those are absolutely, you know, re
relevant to playing quarterback in in
this league. So, there's an adjustment
period. Look, I've said this publicly.
It's the hardest position to play in
sports. And it's not like, well, what
you did in college is automatically
going to translate over. There's certain
skills that are going to translate over,
but it's not always just, you know, one
for one.
>> I think there was a question over here.
Yep.
>> Yeah. Seems like every year at the
combine there are fewer prospects who
participate in the full workout and all
of the drills. I think last year 61% of
players ran a 40 whereas 10 years ago it
was about 80%. Does that matter to you
as an evaluator if you're going to see
them run later at the pro day? Does it
matter if they're doing it here?
>> You'll probably get a different answer
from everybody. It doesn't matter to me
honestly. Whatever they do here, they
do. It doesn't really matter. So
eventually you'd like to have a time.
Okay. Like how relevant is that time? I
mean, let's go back to Lacier, how many
years ago, right? He ran, what was his
time? I don't know, 465. I mean, he's
not a 465. The guy plays 45 or below,
and he's a football player. He's one of
our best players. So, if we're so caught
up in, well, the guy ran this, okay,
well, it's a data point. All right. Does
it affect their play if they choose not
to do something here? Ultimately, it's a
player's prerogative. So, our job is to
understand the thought process, the
rationale behind why they do or not do
something. Okay? and then figure out,
all right, does this player fit in our
building or not? And then ultimately
when they walk in our building, they're
all kind of starting from scratch. And
so we're going to teach them and train
them and provide them the resources that
they need to be successful. So whatever
they decide to do here, no, I'd say
sometimes they listen to the wrong
people because they're getting
misinformation. So you kind of have to
balance that off here a little bit. So
our job is to understand it, not to make
a judgment about it, and ultimately make
a good decision that we feel is in the
best interest of our team and
organization.
>> So what does matter to you here? We got
a growing number of teams that are
taking this week off because they don't
want to taint their process with getting
to meet the guy. What What do you make
of that approach?
>> Yeah, I'd say a couple. Just speaking of
that, I think just the timing and the
scheduling kind of leads to these wide
gaps. So, I think everybody has to look
at it. Okay, how can we be most
efficient with our times? And I think
when you look at the league, there was I
don't know there's 10 new head coaches,
right? Separate from that, there's
another I don't know 10 to 12
coordinators that have turned over,
right? So you're talking about massive
coaching turnover. So this is probably a
good opportunity for those teams to kind
of spend together as a staff and kind of
go through self scout, look at the team,
what happened this year, who are the
players coming back. So it's all about
resource and time allocation. I say
specifically for the Texans, we try to
maximize our opportunity to kind of
spend one-on-one time with the player. A
lot of times it's our first introduction
with the player, meeting them on a
personal level. We're trying to get to
know them personally. And then the more
time and the more touch points that we
have for them, it's just going to help
us make a good decision. So I think
everybody, every team has to go about
their business however they see fit. And
you certainly understand why some teams
are here, why some teams are not here.
In the end, you got to do what they
feel, you know, is best for themselves.
We try to be as efficient with our time
and resources as possible, you know,
which is why Dik and I are here. I mean,
I'll I mean, I'll speak for both of us.
None of us are going to be here
starting, you know, Friday when the
workouts actually start. So, I mean, we
can watch them on TV and kind of going
to the question a little bit earlier, if
we watch them, we watch them. If we
don't, we don't. Eventually going to get
the information. But I think that
interpersonal element, I'd say that's a
big thing for us here over these next
three to four days.
>> The framework of the league suggests
like if you have a good young
quarterback
on a rookie contract, surrounding him
with the money is is a good way to to
win on that quarterback rookie contract.
Yet, nobody's done it. Do you have any
ideas as to why that hasn't happened?
>> Yeah, I think that whole I think that
whole concept gets a little bit
overblown. So, I mean, again, everybody
everybody's got a salary cap. Everybody
has parameters that they have to operate
in. You have to look at your team and
you're going to allocate resources
across the team. Where's that money
going? Some positions are going to have
a little bit more than others. All
right? Then eventually it's going to
shift to a different position. So,
again, I think the most important thing
is how do you put together the best
team? So, I mean, let's go back and look
at the Super Bowl. I would say when you
look at the teams that were in the Super
Bowl or even the teams kind of in the
championship games and what are the
things that stand out run defense taking
the ball away playing good situational
football. So I mean quarterback's a part
of that. So but okay I mean but that's
why those teams won or that's why those
teams run in that position. So again I
think you kind of see different trends
throughout the league and the league
kind of goes a little bit in cycles. So
again I think that whole concept I think
it gets talked about a lot honestly. I
think it gets overblown cuz I mean I'm
not sure any of us really understand
what it really means. You draft players,
you add them to the team. At some point
you're going to keep certain players,
other players are going to move on. So
how do we put together the best team?
And the goal is to try to keep it as
consistent and competitive as possible
over a long period of time so you don't
have any have any lapses.
>> How's impact to late rounds and is it a
positive or a negative? And can you take
positives and slash negatives out of it?
>> No, it's a great question. Um, I think
what the college kids are going through
and some that put their names in for an
evaluation, let's say they come back as
a fourth to sixth round pick, right?
Okay. Then they look and say, "All
right, here's a signing bonus and a
contract associated with that." All
right. If they have the opportunity to
maybe receive that same amount in
college, maybe they feel the best thing
for them is to go back and to play more
football. So, I think one of the areas
where it's probably helped is you've
seen some players play a lot of
football. they're more prepared to come
into our league and potentially make a
contribution. You have some players, you
know, 45, 50, 60 games played. The more
you play, the more you do something, the
better you're going to get. So, so it
kind of works both ways. And kind of an
earlier question, whatever they decide,
they decide we don't penalize a player
because, okay, he received x amount of
dollars in the NIL. It's what's the
rationale? What's the understanding? Our
job is to understand it, not to pass
judgment. So, I think you've seen a
shift from the number of underassmen. I
think going back however many years was
like a buck 255 almost 130. Now we're at
6570. So it got cut in half. So a lot of
those players are choosing to stay.
That's okay. So we can evaluate who's
available and then we've probably
evaluated the player going back to
school. Maybe a year later we're ahead
in our process because we've done the
work.
>> Go ahead. Follow up to that. would be
can you now judge them from a character
or maturity standpoint because they do
get x amount of dollars rather than
spend the money on the front end if they
haven't had it
>> for sure. Now, what are they all doing
with that money? I mean, that's another
way to look at it. Does he got to have
eight cars and or does he actually have
a financial adviser and he puts it into
an S&P stock index because he's trying
to grow his portfolio? I mean, you got
probably a different thought process
that goes into it. I know what I would
do. I mean, you know, nobody was giving
me any anal money and I wasn't good
enough. But again, it's just understand
their thought process. I I think you do
see a certain level of maturity and
you're seeing more players. I mean,
there's a number of players. We're
talking to players 24, 25, 26 years old.
And then it's like, well, are they too
far along? You're not going to be able
to develop them and you're like worried
about the second contract. Like, we
don't care about any of that. Like,
what's a player? What's a profile? How
does he fit? Is this a player that we
think is going to be an asset to our
program? Great. Then we'll add him to
the team. If he's not, then we'll move
on to another one. What are you guys
going to need to see out of U Jaylen
Null this off season or coming in the
next year to maybe see him on the field
a little bit more?
>> Yeah, I mean he's got a great attitude.
He's actually been in a weight room
training. I mean we've had probably 10
to 12 guys that haven't stopped working
out since the season has ended. So Jay's
got a great attitude. He's going to be a
good player in this league. He's going
to our players are going to earn their
opportunity with their performance. So
the better you are, the more
opportunities you get, the more you do
with them, the more you're going to
receive. So love Jay Nol. Glad he's on
the team. Really helped us as a
returner. Um, and then when he had
opportunities offensively, he was
productive with those touches. So, I
think between him and Hig and we got
another group of young players as well.
I mean, going from year one to year two,
the investment that you make in your
preparation and the work getting
yourself ready for that second season,
that's where you can make a lot of
gains.
>> Speaking of players, after CJ's
performance in the playoffs, just
curious confidence rattle even a little
bit like you mentioned the stock market
to go down even a point.
>> Uh, yeah, our he's our quarterback. He
ain't going anywhere. We have a lot of
confidence, a lot of belief. I mean, I'd
say the philosophy that Demo and I have,
we're going to support our players and
do everything we can to kind of help
them. And this league is about ups and
downs. I mean, nothing's perfect. I
mean, there's no team that is undefeated
unless I miss something this year. So,
that's not going to happen. You know, by
and large, you're probably going to lose
five or six games. Got to be some margin
on either side. You're going to have
some good plays. You're going to have
some bad plays. You're going to have
some good games. You're going to have
some bad games. Okay. How do you bounce
back? How do you handle that? So, it's
just I mean, this league is a one game
at a time proposition. and how you
handle it, every situation ultimately is
going to determine your success and your
longevity. So, no loss. I mean, look,
the stock market's been going down for
five days. So, everybody's probably
panic selling. So, you know, the really
what you're doing is you be investing
more. So, but anyways, we have a lot of
confidence in CJ. We got a lot of
confidence in our players and I'm glad
he's our quarterback. Go ahead.
>> You mentioned Lacer and time and things
of that nature. To follow up on the
earlier question, when you watch
players, you know, go through workouts,
how much do you watch their movement
skills? Theoretically, like if a guy
runs a 40, but he's kind of running like
a track runner, not a football player,
how much do you kind of evaluate that?
What's the overall evaluation of the
actual movement skills to get the drill
done versus doing it in a way that
transferable onto a football?
>> Yeah. Know, it's a great question. I
mean, it's really what are you going to
ask that player to do? What's their
skill set specific to the position that
they play? So, with corners, it's not
just running in a straight line. It's
your awareness, your eyes, your level of
instinctiveness, your ability to process
information at a high rate of speed,
breaking on the ball, breaking on the
throw. And you got to be able to
delineate between time speed and track
speed and game speed. Like in the end,
how fast does the player play? Sometimes
guys play their time speed. Some guys,
they don't play to their time speed. And
then what's the rationale behind that?
So again, it's specific to the position.
I mean, I've stood up here and said
this. I mean, the whole offensive line
running to 40 times is asinine. Like,
they're never going to run 40 yards. So,
they're going to move in a short space.
Can they bend their knees? Can they move
the line of scrimmage? Can they play
with good technique? I would say, you
know, not a lot of them play with good
technique. So, we have to coach them to
play with better technique to move
bodies and move the line of scrimmage.
So, we're going to look at everything.
There's certain skills that are going to
be transferable based on a position, but
we factor everything in. And sometimes
there's a correlation between, well, if
the guy has these metrics and these
measurables, it potentially could lead
to this result. Not all the time, but
again, speed is speed. I mean, it's not
I'm going to say it's not important, but
it's just one data point. And how does
that affect I mean, look, you guys can
go back through and look at like some of
the fastest times in the history of the
combine. The list of players that have
actually been worth a lick. I mean, it's
a pretty short list, right? Doesn't mean
that every fast guy is a bad player. It
just means you got to take it sometimes
with a grain of salt. And there's more
to it than what the guy does out there
with his shorts on that he's been
training basically for six weeks. Hasn't
done anything else. So, we got to take
all that into consideration. To
>> follow up on that, Nick, to follow up on
that, is there anything about this
combine week that you'd like to see
changed or different?
>> Well, I think the the main thing is the
location. There's not a better location
to have something like this than
Indianapolis. So, it's logistically
works on a lot of levels. It's kind of
centrally located. I mean, I know
there's been a lot of talk about moving
to Combine, but I mean, what Jeff Foster
and his staff do is incredible. It's a
great location. You got access, you got
everything you need. You got the hotels,
you got the dome, you got the medical
center, you got everything. So,
logistically, this is a good spot from a
scheduling standpoint. Some of the other
things, I mean, look, it's made for TV.
Let's be honest, right? I mean, that's
what the focus is. So, I would say we're
less worried about the TV component and
more worried about just understanding
the player, getting to know the players
a little bit. So whatever the schedule
is, I mean the one thing about football,
people in general for the most part
pretty flexible. So whatever it is, like
we'll adjust, we'll adapt and we'll
figure it out and make it work. I mean
that's how we approach it. That's how
Demo and I think. So whatever it is,
like we'll be there and we'll be ready
to go.
>> What's some of the biggest
characteristics that you look for just
in adding players mentally or
physically?
>> Yeah, mindset. Um selflessness. I mean
our program is about team first and
doing the right thing for the team.
maybe when everything isn't perfect for
you. Um, look, our defense is about
violence of physicality. So, if you
don't have that, you're probably not
going to work here. I mean, it's just
the reality of it. I mean, you can go
play somewhere else, no problem. Um, but
we're looking for players with a certain
mentality and a certain mindset,
honestly, not just on defense, but
offensively as well. So, we're trying to
build a strong, fast, big, physical team
that can compete on a week- toeek basis
regardless of the circumstances or
conditions. So, who are the players that
have those qualities that, okay, are
going to be able to go out there and
handle that on a week-to-eek basis?
>> You have uh one BT under contract past
this season. How how important is it to
look not just the next season, but two
years down the line where the contract
situations kind of balancing
long-termish moves and short-term?
>> It's twofold, Landry. You know, you're
trying to take, you know, like you said,
we got a number of that are free agents
this year. All right. Probably going to
lose some of them. Maybe we'll get some
of them back. Um, I'd say Tommy Togei is
an example of a player where, you know,
we felt like again that he was going to
be competitive, try to get ahead of that
a little bit. So, again, some of it is
what's the uh willingness or openness on
the other side. You know, there's two
parties that are involved here in
negotiation. So, we'll have dialogue at
any point, any time. Um, I think people
know how we operate. Um, I'm kind of to
the point, get to the bottom line, and
if it's going to work, it's going to
work. If it's not, no problem. We
understand that. and then we can kind of
plan accordingly. So, um not going to
rule any we're never going to rule
anything out, but you know, some years
it's going to look a little bit
different relative to others.
>> Um Ed Ingram is one of your free agents.
How did you think about he played and
what do you think about his potential?
>> Yeah, Ed had a great year. Honestly,
probably had the best year of his
career. Um you know, for the most part,
he was out there. He missed a couple
games there with injuries, but good kid.
He's strong. He's physical. He plays
violent in the running game. Um you saw
that on tape quite a bit. Um pretty good
pass protection. So, we're working
through that process, you know, right
now. So, we'll have discussion with him
and his representatives and, you know,
we'll kind of see how agency he goes.
Um, but I'm glad he was here. I mean, a
player that we feel benefited from our
program and honestly sometimes a change
of scenery is good. Um, probably worked
out for him and kind of worked out for
us as well. But, glad Ed was on the team
here this year.
>> All right. Thank you. Appreciate it.